Discover the Legend
Sinbad: The Fifth Voyage is a fantasy, family, adventure
film directed by Shahin Sean Solimon.
When the Sultan's first born is taken by an evil sorcerer, Sinbad is tasked
with traveling to a desert of magic and creatures to save her.
Sinbad, played by Shahin Sean Solimon.
Narrator (Voice), played by Patrick Stewart.
The Deev, played by Said Faraj.
Zoreh, played by Lorna Raver.
Miriam, played by Mariam Vardani.
Death, played by Isaac C. Singleton, Jr..
The 7th Voyage of Sinbad is a 1958 American fantasy adventure film directed by Nathan Juran and
starring Kerwin Mathews, Kathryn Grant, Torin Thatcher, Richard Eyer, and Alec Mango.
It was distributed by Columbia Pictures and produced by Charles H.
It was the first of three Sinbad feature films from Columbia, the later two from the 1970s being
The Golden Voyage of Sinbad (1973) and Sinbad and the Eye of the Tiger (1977).
All three Sinbad films were conceptualized by Ray Harryhausen using Dynamation, the
full color widescreen stop-motion animation technique that he created.
While similarly named, the film does not follow the storyline of the tale "The Seventh Voyage of Sinbad
the Sailor" but instead has more in common with the Third and Fifth voyages of Sinbad.
The 7th Voyage of Sinbad was selected in 2008 for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by
the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".